# EFTHIMIOS VLAHOS – DATA SCIENTIST

vlahos89@gmail.com | (516)-606-0942 | linkedin.com/in/efthimios-vlahos | github.com/EfthimiosVlahos | East Meadow, NY 11554

### PROFFESIONAL SUMMARY

Currently a Data Analyst at Microsoft, I am a dedicated professional with an MSc in Applied Mathematics and Statistics, specializing in Data Science. As an aspiring ML Engineer, I bring over 3 years of experience in data science, adept in utilizing SQL, Python, and R for data analysis, visualization, and machine learning workflows to effectively transform complex datasets into business growth insights.

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming, Libraries, & Cloud Computing: Python(TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, mlflow, Pandas, NumPy, NLTK, Trax, JAX), R, C++, Bash, SQL(PostgreSQL, MySQL, BigQuery), AWS(SageMaker, EC2, S3, Lambda), GCP(Compute Engine, Vertex AI, Auto ML, DataProc, DataFlow), Apache(Spark, Hadoop, Beam, Hive, Airflow)
- Machine Learning: Supervised & Unsupervised Learning, Deep Learning(CNNs, RNNs, GRUs, LSTM, Transformers), NLP, Predictive Modeling,
   Time Series Analysis, Feature Engineering, Model Evaluation, Model Tuning, Validation Methods, Optimization Techniques, Hyperparameter Tuning
- DevOps, Data Visualization & MLOps: Docker, Kubernetes, MLflow, Kubeflow, DagsHub, Mage, Tableau, Power BI, Looker, Git, GitHub

## PROJECTS/PORTFOLIO

Chest Cancer Detection (Python, TensorFlow, MLflow, DagsHub, Docker, Flask, AWS, MLOps)

New York, NY

Nov 2023 - Dec 2023

Link: Chest Cancer Detection Project

- Integrated MLflow and DAGsHub to manage the machine learning lifecycle, enhancing experiment tracking and model performance evaluation, resulting in a 20% boost in model accuracy and a 30% reduction in development cycle time.
- Spearheaded a deployment strategy, utilizing Docker for containerization and AWS for cloud hosting, resulting in a scalable web service.
- Leveraged the VGG16 CNN model for the classification of chest cancer from CT scan images, achieving an 85% accuracy rate.

E-Commerce Customer Satisfaction (Python, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, XGBoost, ZenML, MLflow, Optuna, Streamlit)

New York, NY

Link: E-commerce Project

Aug 2023 - Nov 2023

- Successfully integrated MLflow with ZenML, enhancing the machine learning lifecycle from data ingestion to model deployment, resulting in
  increased robustness and scalability of models in real-world applications.
- Enhanced RandomForest model performance by 15% in predictive accuracy, as measured by comprehensive testing, by implementing
  Optuna-based hyperparameter tuning and refining model parameters.

News Research Tool Development (Python, Streamlit, Langchain, OpenAI, NLP)

Link: LLM Project

New York, NY

- Jan 2023 Feb 2023
- Implemented advanced NLP techniques and leveraged OpenAI embeddings along with FAISS vector stores to create a dynamic system for
  efficient document splitting, embedding generation, and indexing, facilitating rapid and precise information retrieval from extensive news articles.
- Engineered a proof-of-concept for efficient information retrieval from article chunks, accelerating research, streamlining data retrieval, and enhancing decision-making in news analysis.

NYC TLC Predictive Modeling (Python, SQL, GCP, BigQuery, Mage, Tableau)

New York, NY

Link: TLC Capstone Project

Jun 2022 - Jul 2022

- Designed a data processing architecture using GCP and BigQuery, effectively streamlining workflows with the Mage Data Pipeline Tool.
- Applied advanced regression techniques to achieve a 92% adjusted R^2 score on test set for predicting taxi fare amounts.
- Conducted strategic A/B testing to reveal the impact of payment types on fares which led to valuable insights into fare dynamics.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

New York, NY

Microsoft

Nov 2023 - Present

- Led the development and implementation of NLP techniques to detect hallucinations in AI-generated text, enhancing the accuracy and reliability of machine-generated information.
- · Addressed complex challenges in AI-generated content, strategizing to improve response accuracy and overall quality.
- Communicated key findings and strategies for hallucination detection to stakeholders, collaborating with data analysts for continuous improvement.

Data Analyst Intern

New York, NY

KPMG

Jun 2023 - Oct 2023

- Advised clients on customer targeting by assessing data quality and analyzing demographics, leading to targeted outreach.
- Analyzed data to target high-value customers based on demographics and attributes.
- . Developed dashboards to effectively communicate visual findings and insights. Assessed data quality and completeness in preparation for analysis.

## **EDUCATION**

SUNY STONY BROOK UNIVERSITY, College of Engineering and Applied Sciences

Stony Brook, NY

Masters in Applied Mathematics & Statistics, Data Science Concentration

May 2023

- Cumulative GPA: 3.5/4.0; Dean's List 2022-2023
- Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, Big Data Analysis, Data Structures and Algorithms, Linear Programming, Probability Theory, Numerical Analysis

**CUNY HUNTER COLLEGE** 

Manhattan, NY

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics & Physics, Minor in Computer Science

June 2020

- Cumulative GPA: 3.7/4.0; Dean's List 2016-2019
- Relevant Coursework: Intermediate Mechanics, Quantum Mechanics, Linear Algebra, Abstract Algebra, Vector Calculus, Mathematical Analysis I & II